Let someone say, "Thank You, Jesus!"
Let someone say, "I am under His eyes".
Say, "I am under His eyes; nothing out of God's control can happen to me.
I am safe!
Thank You, Jesus!"
Give thanks to Him once again!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brethren, there are two sides to life.
First, we have the spiritual side -
the ultimate conclusion where satan was defeated.
Second, we have the natural side -
where people try to figure God out with their natural mind.
When these two dimensions of life are clearly discerned,
only then will we be able to navigate and negotiate the spiritual war around us.
We are not fighting flesh and blood;
we are not fighting people with flesh and blood.
We are fighting someone without a body.
We are fighting spirit beings - spirit to spirit.
The battle is the Lord's.
The believer who walks in the natural is no match for satan.
But glory be to God Almighty that victory is ours.
Let someone say, "Victory is mine".
The natural man, the man of the intellect, cannot understand
or receive the things of the Spirit of God.
That's why the Bible urges every believer today to get their eyes fixed
not on what is seen but on what is unseen.
Say, "Neighbour, walk by faith, not by sight".
A Christian should be careful of what he's looking at
because what he is looking at can influence his thoughts and his future actions.
Life is a warfare.
Life is a battlefield, where only the serious-minded can be victorious.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Life is a battlefield, where only the serious-minded are victorious.
Say, "Neighbour, are you ready for the battle?
Neighbour, get your heart set.
Get your mind set."
This leads us to our message this morning: THE BATTLE IN YOUR THOUGHTS.
Let someone say, "The battle in your thoughts".
Let me take you to our proof text, the book of 2 Corinthians 10.
I will start my reading from verse 2.
"But I beg you that when I am present I may not be bold with that confidence
by which I intend to be bold against some,
who think of us as if we walked according to the flesh."
Verse 3.
"For though we walk in the flesh, we do not war according to the flesh."
Verse 4.
"For the weapons of our warfare are not carnal but mighty in God for pulling down strongholds,
casting down arguments and every high thing that exalts itself against the knowledge of God,
bringing every thought into captivity to the obedience of Christ..."
Bringing every thought into captivity of the obedience to Christ.
The devil is our common enemy
but he hates our looking at things from God's point of view,
because he knows that the man who learns to walk in Christ Jesus,
in faith, has satan under his feet.
That is why he does not want any believer to walk in faith
but rather he wants them to walk by sight.
The battle we face in our daily living is with our senses -
what you see, what you hear and what your circumstances look like.
Our senses point us to the physical world, to the natural world,
whereas the Bible says the believer does not have strength as long as he operates in the natural.
The believer does not have strength as long as he operates,
he makes decisions in the natural.
Those who rely on sense knowledge cannot see beyond now.
But those who operate in the spirit are those who rely on revelation truth.
I mean the mind of God, through the revealing Word of God.
Say, "Neighbour, we don't walk by sight but by faith.
Walk by faith, not by sight".
Let me give you an example: In the Book of Matthew 16, it is all about Simon Peter.
Matthew chapter 16 from verse 15.
Jesus asked, "Who do people say I am?"
Simon said, "One of the prophets".
But Jesus looked around his disciples and asked them, "You, who do you say I am?"
Verse 16.
Simon Peter listened to his divine nature;
I mean, he listened to the testimony of his heart and
upon hearing the revealing Word of God, he confessed Christ as the Son of the Living God
and received approval and blessing from Jesus.
But in the other moment in verse 23, when Jesus predicted His death at the Cross
for the salvation of our souls, to fulfill the Scripture,
the same Simon Peter listened to the feelings of his human nature and stood against the Lord
and Jesus said, "Get behind me, satan, for you are mindful not of the things of God but of man".
What does this mean to you and me?
Looking at life, its storms and adversities from the natural or human point of view
is a trap of the enemy to derail you from your natural focus.
Say, "Neighbour, looking at life, its storms, its troubles and its adversities
from the human point of view is a trap of the enemy to derail you from your focus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, watch and pray".
Man's conscience is God's instrument for discernment.
My heart, my conscience is God's instrument for discernment - therefore, watch!
Our heart is the watchman.
Your heart is the watchman.
Prophet T.B. Joshua says, "I do not see satan in the natural; I see him in the spiritual realm".
Therefore, if your heart sleeps, the devil takes the opportunity to attack.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What makes your heart sleep? Ask your neighbour.
"Neighbour, what makes your heart sleep?"
Negative thoughts, anger, offence, fits of rage.
These are the things that make your heart sleep because they damage the heart.
Say, "Neighbour, discipline your heart".
Say, "Neighbour, take care of your heart.
Watch over your heart".
Why?
Our heart is the realm of desires and emotions.
Vain and idle thoughts are products of a vain and idle heart.
Vain and idle thoughts and words are products of a vain and idle heart;
therefore, discipline your heart.
Because only dedication and discipline are the fruit of victory
to overcome the battle of thoughts raging within you.
Dedication and discipline are the means of victory
against the battle of thoughts going on inside of you.
Therefore, capture your thoughts for the glory of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How do we discipline our heart?
As you are sitting down, many thoughts are going on.
You are here because you face a giant.
You are here saying, "When will I separate myself from this woman?"
Shall I divorce her? Shall I leave?
Shall I close this business? Shall I have another one?"
Many thoughts are going on in our hearts today.
Discipline your heart.
How do we discipline our heart?
Prophet T.B. Joshua says, "Give your heart a job; don't let your heart give you a job".
Say, "Neighbour, give your heart a job; don't let your heart give you a job".
If you don't give an assignment to your heart, your heart will give an assignment to itself.
Your heart will keep roaming about, taking you to the past,
from one thought to another and put you into trouble.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Discipline your heart to become your servant, not your master
so that you can be able to concentrate on the things that are in the spirit.
Discipline your heart; discipline your mind.
Discipline your heart to become your servant not your master so that you can think,
concentrate on the things of the Spirit because your thoughts have presence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What does it mean that your thoughts have presence?
There are many thoughts going through your heart today.
That thought will lead you to action.
That thought can lead you to success or failure because man exercises the will through the mind.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, your thoughts have presence".
This means, what happens in your heart will happen in time
because our life reflects what is in our heart.
What happens in your heart will happen in time because our life reflects what is in our heart.
This means our lives will always go to the level of our thoughts
because our words and our actions express our thoughts, which are the seeds of our lives.
Your life will always go to the level of your thoughts
because your words and your actions express your thoughts, which are the seeds of your life.
A man's life is what his thoughts make it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
A man's life is what he is thinking all day long.
What you are thinking about - within you - that is where the unending battle starts.
It is only by making what is right that can get you to the victory in this unending spiritual warfare.
It is only by the right choice you make that can take you to victory
in the face of this endless spiritual warfare.
It is an unending battle, an unending warfare.
Why?
Because we battle with our thoughts throughout our lifetime.
My heart is the communication point, contact point,
between God's suggestion to do what is right or the devil's suggestion to do what is wrong.
Our thoughts have presence.
Let someone say, "A man's life is what his thoughts make it".
There will be a constant battle of thoughts in your heart.
You have to be ready for the battle and face it.
There are two opposing forces: Right and wrong, faith and doubt, good and evil.
Say, "Brethren, great thoughts produce great decisions".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let someone say, "Victory is mine because I am not alone; the battle is the Lord's.
Say, "Neighbour, who is your strength?
The Lord is my strength".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The battle on the outside is only a reflection of the battle on the inside.
Let me give you an example.
In the Book of 2 Kings 6:15-16, let's look at the notable biblical hero Prophet Elisha.
The Bible says, there was a war going on.
And any time the king of the opposing army was setting up his strategy in his room,
talking to his generals, all his plan was revealed to Israel.
They said, "Who is betraying us?"; someone said, "It is the Prophet Elisha
who is revealing far away the word you are speaking in your bedroom".
They said, "Let's go and catch him".
When they woke up in the morning, the town was surrounded by armies.
The servant of the prophet saw it and got overwhelmed and scared.
Naturally, Prophet Elisha and his servant were defenceless
in the face of the heavily armed Syrian army.
That is why it was not a surprise to see his servant lose balance and emotion
out of much agitation and fear.
Because he concentrated, he focused on what the immediate situation was saying,
not on what God had to say.
But Elisha, being a man of faith, remained calm, calculated and determined.
Why?
Because he was able to see beyond the situation at hand.
He was able to be calm and determined because he was able to see the other side.
Let someone say, "See the other side".
When he saw the spiritual realm, he knew that his God
had made adequate provision for him to face the enemy
and God gave him the victory, total victory, absolute victory.
Let someone say, "God is faithful".
Encourage your neighbour, say, "Neighbour, fear not".
No matter your trouble, you are in His presence;
He is the same yesterday, today and forever.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When the prophet saw his servant was frightened, he said to him,
"Do not be afraid of the calamities of this world, because fear brings torment, anguish, anxiety".
Rather than magnifying the cause of your fear, equip yourself with the thoughts of God.
Let someone say, "The thoughts of God".
Let someone say, "The mind of Christ; the mind of God".
You have to know God's opinion over your situation - that's the key, that's the way out.
Brethren, no matter the war going on inside of you, right now as you're listening to me,
no matter your giant, we have a Friend -
the man of God calls Him the Wonderful Unseen Guest - the Holy Spirit,
who will conquer every giant in your life today.
Do you believe that?
Say, "I am not alone!"
Brethren, if the One who overcomes dwells in you,
you will overcome every obstacle today, in the name of Jesus!
Now, what is the lesson of this.
When you know God's opinion about your situation, life, business, marriage,
you will fear no more, worry no more, doubt no more
because that will impart a strength to endure whatever you're going through
because Someone is aware.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Finally, brethren, faith is the means of victory in this battle of thoughts.
Why?
Faith comes when the Word of God prevails over the thinking processes.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, get ready for the victory!"
Are you ready for the victory?
Remember, David wasn't afraid.
Say, "Victory is mine today".
Say, "Today, my enemy has made a big mistake
by allowing me to be here in the presence of the Lord!"
Today, you are more than a conqueror!
You will overcome!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Prophet T.B. Joshua says, "There is a difference between meditation and thinking".
He says meditation has to do with the knowledge of Heaven,
knowledge of the will of God in your matter, through the revealing Word of God.
Thinking has to do with the senses, with the problem at hand.
That's why thinking leads to depression.
It damages the heart;
it brings worry and worrying destroys our sense of judgement.
The Bible says as you meditate on the Word of God,
you will overcome every negative thought.
As you meditate on the Word of God, you will overcome every negative thought.
Those negative thoughts triggered by satan may persist in staying
but refuse to accommodate those thoughts, refuse to put them into words and they will die unborn.
The Scriptures say, submit to God and resist the evil one.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, the way out for you has come.
The way out for me has come".
No matter what happens, no matter what comes, speak only the Word of God,
speak only the Word of faith over your situation, marriage, business, health,
over every aspect of your life.
If your heart and mind are filled with the Word of Jesus,
you will overcome every obstacle in your life,
you will overcome every trial that comes upon your way!
And such will be your case today, if you believe.
Do you believe?
Do you believe that?
Begin to rejoice!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Any moment from now, you will begin to see the name of Jesus Christ working in the Spirit.
You will see the Living Word of God working in the Spirit - uprooting, tearing down,
destroying all the strongholds of the devil against your life.
You will see His power and anointing that breaks the yoke.
Therefore, take heart.
Let someone say, "Take heart".
Jesus cares because Jesus sees.
He knows you; He knows your past, present and future.
May God bless His Word.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 16/02/2019
RV: Pavel Tatyana 11/03/2019